cyclingexpress.com 2012-12-27

# Privacy & Security

#### Security

##### Secure Shopping at Cycling Express

Cycling Express strives to be the Australia’s favorite, top value, and best service one stop bike shop, so we take our customers security very, very seriously. 

The security measures we have in place are industry benchmarks and as close to impenetrable as possible. We review all of our security measures on an ongoing basis to make sure that they are current with industry standards. 

When you pay for your order at Cycling Express with a credit or debit card, Securepay, one of Australia’s leading online secure banks processes your protected payment. This means that payment is made instantly through Securepay’s safe banking system allowing Cycling Express to avoid the need to ever see or store your card details like some other websites. 

However, if you are still concerned about sharing your card details you can also pay at Cycling Express using PayPal; this way you can choose not to use a credit or debit card if you prefer not to. 

##### Other ways you can prevent fraud

Cycling Express is yet to have any fraudulent transactions occur but just to make sure there are a couple of simple things you can do to decrease or eliminate the possibility of fraudulent activity. 

You can avoid anyone attempting to use you identity by using a strong password combining letters and numbers, not writing your password down anywhere and by using an up to date web browser (Safari, Firefox, Internet Explorer). Changing your password regularly and not using the same password on multiple sites will also help prevent any possible illegal activity.

If you are using a public computer, such as in an Internet café, at school or on a shared computer, always log out when you've finished using Cycling Express. Remember that Cycling Express will not e-mail or call you to ask you to disclose or verify your password, credit card or bank account number. So, you should only give out this information when you contact us directly or when you check-out on the Cycling Express website. 

If you receive unsolicited e-mails that ask you to provide your Cycling Express password or any personal or banking information, do not reply to the request and immediately report the incident to us so that we can investigate. You can contact us at help@cyclingexpress.com or via our direct hotline between the hours of 9am-5pm AEST. 

##### Paypal at Cycling Express

If you decide you would prefer to check out using PayPal you can do this without opening a PayPal account, as Paypal now offer direct payment using Credit or Debit. Alternatively if you already have an account with PayPal you can use this to check out quickly and securely. Paypal does not charge an admin fee to use their checkout facility. 

##### Purchasing with PayPal at Cycling Express

Simply add the items you would like to purchase to your basket, then checkout in the usual way. Next, select PayPal as the payment method and follow the provided instructions.

At this point you will be redirected to PayPal’s secure checkout facility. Here simply choose how your payment method and then click the 'Review Payment' button to return to Cycling Express. 

Check all the order details are correct and then click 'Confirm Order'. PayPal will then charge you for the order total. If the order is successfully created you will be redirected to a thank you page showing your order number and items ordered.

You will subsequently receive two emails, one from Cycling Express to confirm the order you have just made and one from PayPal to confirm your payment.

Please note; orders over $600 in value or containing a bike will require you to use a PayPal 'confirmed' address for security purposes. You can create a 'confirmed' address by signing up for a PayPal account and fulfilling PayPal’s requirements for a confirmed address. Alternatively, to avoid this you can simply pay with a credit card or Visa Debit card. 

##### Priority Dispatch Feature

We don’t have a priority dispatch feature like some other online sites. At Cycling Express we treat every order as a priority dispatch without charging you any extra. 

This means that your order will be dispatched within 24 hours* of our having received it no matter what! 

*Business Hours. 

#### Privacy

##### Cycling Express Privacy Policy

The Privacy Policy of Cycling Express is bound by the Commonwealth Privacy Act and the ten National Privacy Principles for the handling of personal information, which are set out in that act. Our policies, processes and systems have been developed to ensure we comply with all our obligations under the Privacy Act.

Cycling Express understands and appreciates how important it is to safeguard your personal information. This privacy policy explains how your personal information will be treated when you deal with our business.

##### The information we collect

Each time someone visits our site, our web server collects the following types of information:

  * The number of users who visit
  * The date and time of visits
  * The number of pages viewed
  * How users navigate through the site

No attempts are made to identify anyone browsing our site. The data is only captured so that we can accurately evaluate the quality of our content and make improvements for you.

##### Cookies

Information may also be collected in the form of cookies when you use our web site. A cookie is a piece of data stored on your computer, which contains information relating to your use of our web site. When you visit our web site, cookies may record details about your computer and your use of our site, such as what pages you view and download from the site. 

We use cookies for internal management purposes only. If you do not wish to use cookies, you can set your browser so that it will not accept them. Cookies that are sent to your computer cannot read your hard drive, obtain any information from your browser or command your computer to perform any particular action in any way. They are designed so that they cannot be sent to another site or be retrieved by any site other than Cycling Express.

##### What type of personal information do we collect?

Cycling Express collects personal information that is necessary to review employment applications, maintain our relationships with our customers, administer any award program or competition we may run, market our products and deal with enquiries and complaints regarding those products.

The personal information we collect for promotional and business purposes is generally limited to contact details (name, address and phone no.). If you apply for a job at Cycling Express, we will collect information related to your employment history. If you lodge a complaint with us, we will record details and the nature of the complaint.

Personal information about our business customers is usually collected from direct contact between you and our representatives.

Personal information about customers is collected by us if you:

• place an order with Cycling Express;

• request a cost estimation of work to be carried out by Cycling Express; or

• lodge a complaint/enquiry about our business.

If you forward information to us either electronically (eg. in an email) or by sending it to us as a hard copy document, we will collect that information and use it for the purposes for which you have provided it to us.

##### How do we collect personal information?

Cycling Express will take reasonable commercial steps to ensure that all information we collect, use or disclose is accurate, complete, up to date and stored in a secure environment accessed only by authorised persons.

We will, where commercially practicable and permitted by law, destroy or permanently de-identify personal information that is no longer needed.

Personal information about customers is collected by us if you:

  * place an order with Cycling Express;
  * request a cost estimation of work to be carried out by Cycling Express; or
  * lodge a complaint/enquiry about our business.

If you forward information to us either electronically (eg. in an email) or by sending it to us as a hard copy document, we will collect that information and use it for the purposes for which you have provided it to us.

##### How your personal information will be managed

Cycling Express will take reasonable commercial steps to ensure that all information we collect, use or disclose is accurate, complete, up to date and stored in a secure environment accessed only by authorised persons. 

We will, where commercially practicable and permitted by law, destroy or permanently de-identify personal information that is no longer needed.

##### How your personal information will be used

Cycling Express will use the personal information provided to us for one or more of the following purposes (depending on the circumstances):

  * review employment applications;
  * maintain and develop our business relationships with our business customers;
  * respond to and analyse complaints and enquiries regarding Cycling Express;
  * administer award programs we may run from time to time;
  * notify you from time to time of special events or offers and services Cycling Express may provide; and
  * fulfil all legal and regulatory requirements of Cycling Express.

Your use of the Cycling Express web site constitutes consent to the storage of your information by Cycling Express and any contractor providing hosting services to Cycling Express.

If you do not wish to receive information about additional promotions and services offered by Cycling Express, you can let us know by sending our Privacy Officer a message by post, fax or email at any of the addresses set out below.

##### Will my personal information be disclosed to a third party?

The personal information Cycling Express collects from you is strictly confidential. We will not disclose that information to any third parties other than:

  * related bodies corporate of Cycling Express;
  * any contractor Cycling Express engages for web-hosting services;
  * as we may be required to do by law;
  * or otherwise with your consent.

Cycling Express will take reasonable steps to ensure that any personal information disclosed to a third party is protected by that party in accordance with the Privacy Act.

###### How you can access your personal information

On request, you may have access to your personal information held by Cycling Express, except in circumstances where access may be denied under the Privacy Act or other law. Examples of these circumstances are:

  * where providing access will pose an unreasonable impact on the privacy of another individual;
  * where providing access would be unlawful, would pose a threat to the life or health of an individual, may prejudice an investigation of possible unlawful activity, may prejudice enforcement of laws or denying access is specifically authorised by law.

To make a request for your personal information, please contact our Privacy Officer (contact details below). We will endeavour to acknowledge a request for personal information within 14 days and provide the information as requested within 30 days. If personal information is provided to you as the result of a request, you may be charged a fee for costs incurred in providing that information such as photocopying, administration and postage. If access is denied we will provide you with reasons for our decision.

##### How you can correct your personal information

If you believe that the personal information we hold about you is inaccurate, incomplete or not up to date please let us know. Provided we agree with you, we will correct it. If we do not agree with you, we will place a statement of what you allege is correct where that information is kept and accessed.

##### Will this privacy policy change?

We reserve the right to change this privacy policy at any time by publishing the varied privacy policy on our web site. The varied policy terms will apply from the date they are posted on our web site. You accept that by doing this, Cycling Express has provided you with sufficient notice of the variation and agree you will be provided with no separate notification.

##### How to contact us

If you have any queries or complaints in regard to our collection, use or management of your personal information, please contact:

Cycling Express  
PO Box 199, Kangaroo Ground, Vic. Australia 3097  
Manager
